#### Giuseppe Di Guglielmo

Web Developer with a focus on UI/UX based in Zurich

## Frontend Software Engineer 80-100%

+41 79 715 48 06 hello@vonwilhelm.ch

Dear Ms. Kadar,

For the past six months, I have been sharing with my friends my desire to work in the field of sustainability. After reading your job description and learning about ecoinvent, I am thrilled to have found the perfect company. As you search for a front-end developer with a keen eye for UX/UI, I believe to be an ideal candidate.

Before joining a professional development team, I worked as a self-employed web developer for almost two years. During this time, I fully devoted myself to improving my programming skills and studied topics related to UX/UI.

At Constructor Learning (formerly Propulsion Academy), I have been working as a software engineer and instructor for over a year. In this role, I have contributed to various projects, including the company's website, internal tools like the application dashboard, and the backend API. With the freedom to propose and design new components using Figma, I had the opportunity to actively improve our web-based applications and implement innovative, user-centered solutions using ReactJS.

I first joined Constructor Learning as a student in the full stack bootcamp and was then hired as a teaching assistant. Staying informed about new technologies and trends has always come naturally to me. I used this ability to keep the curriculum continuously up-to-date and ensure its relevance and effectiveness. Furthermore, I mentored students by reviewing their coding projects, contributing to their growth and success.

As a colleague, I value transparent communication and critical thinking. I enjoy bringing new ideas to the table by thinking outside the box. A pleasant work environment and respectful interaction in a diverse team are essential to me. I actively live by this philosophy and firmly believe that it leads to collective success.

Your advertised position would offer me a great opportunity to use my experience in development and design to enhance the user experience of your future applications. I would strive to provide the best possible experience for users accessing LCI data and bringing my expertise and personality to your team.

Thank you for considering my application. I am excited about the possibility of becoming part of ecoinvent and working with a team dedicated to sustainability.

Sincerely, Giuseppe Di Guglielmo



### Giuseppe Di Guglielmo

Web Developer since 2020 with a focus on UI/UX.

Brother, friend, godfather. Learner and researcher, always a beginner. Hiker, stroller, dreamer, music lover, team player.

Oerlikonerstrasse 47, 8057 Zurich 12. April 1988 in Berne hello@vonwilhelm.ch, +41 79 715 48 06,

Github LinkedIn

#### Languages

- Fluently German, English, Italian
- BasicSpanish, French

#### References

Daniela Meier
 CMO Constructor Learning
 LinkedIn

more references on demand

#### My Tech Stack

Frontend

HTML, CSS, JS, React, Next, Redux, P5.js, Sass, Tailwind, Styled Components

- Design Figma, InDesign, Illustrator
- Backend/Databases
   PHP, Pyhton, Django, Postgres, Kirby CMS, Rest API
- Dev OpsNginx, Docker, Git, Git-CI processes

#### **Selected Projects**

DANZ Fashion Design, 2021

Responsive web design & web development for fasion designer Mara Danz.

Website

Figma, Vanilla JS, HTML & Sass, Snipcart (E-Commerce), GSAP (Scrollanimations), Kirby CMS

• Richard Frick, 2022

Website programming for graphic designer Richard Frick.

Website Github

Vanilla JS, HTML & Sass, Snipcart, Swiper JS, Kirby CMS

- Further projects
  - O Filipelli, 2020
  - O Flavio Leone, 2021
  - O Romy Gyger, 2021

#### **Professional Experience in Web Development**

# Full-Stack Developer & Instructor Constructor Learning Formerly Propulsion Academy, Zurich June 2022 - today

- O Teaching front-end topics such as React, HTML, CSS & Sass, Node & NPM
- Designing new components for the company's website using Figma and implementing them using Next.js
- Enhancing and optiming back-end functionalities for the internal student management tool (Django)
- Adding and improve features for the internal dashboard displaying data and charts related to course applications (React)

#### ■ Full-Stack Assistant

Constructor Learning Feb - June 2022

- O Revised a modern, comprehensive curriculum for the Full-Stack Bootcamp.
- Wrote, updated, and refactored solutions for the curriculum.
- O Taught front-end topics such as HTML, CSS & Sass.
- Mentored students, supervised their projects, and conducted code reviews.

#### Freelance Web Developer as 'Von Wilhelm'

Nov 2021 - Present (part-time) Apr 2020 - Oct 2021 (full-time)

- O Implemented designs with pixel-perfect accuracy using the Kirby CMS (PHP), JS & Sass.
- Worked closely with the graphic studio KUBA CS in Zurich.
- Designed web interfaces using Figma and Adobe InDesign to create appealing and userfriendly websites.
- Advised and acquired new clients by presenting solutions that support their business goals.

#### **Professional Experience in Architecture**

Building Engineering Technician & IT Manager

Architektur & Baumanagement AG, Lucerne Jun 2015 - Aug 2019

- Building Drafter & IT Manager
   Frieri Architekten AG, Lucerne
   Mar 2012 May 2015
- Course Instructor & Software Support Specialist

IDC AG, Sarnen Nov 2009 - Sep 2011

Education as Building Drafter (Hochbauzeichner)

E+P Architekten AG FH SIA, Solothurn Aug 2005 - Jul 2009

#### **Education**

- Full-Stack Bootcamp React/Django Constructor Learning Nov 2021 - Feb 2022
  - O Ping Pong: A platform for students and learners that simplifies finding part-time jobs.
  - Motion: Social network with features for posts, friend requests, and personal profiles.
  - O Luna: Restaurant review platform with features for creating reviews and comments.
- Interaction Design HF

Schule für Gestaltung (1 semester) Feb 2021 - Jul 2021

 Higher Technical Diploma in Building Engineering

TEKO Schweizerische Fachschule, Lucerne Sep 2012 - Jun 2015

Drafter with Federal Certificate of Competence in Architecture

GIBS, Olten Aug 2005 - Jul 2009